▍2026 美网 男单第一轮
布云朝克特 6-2 6-1 6-1 霍达尔 · 赛后新闻发布会
And what was the secret
这场球赢得这么漂亮
to your successful match?
秘诀是什么？
I think just focus and enjoy.
我想就是专注 然后享受
You know, it's nothing you can lose
反正也输不了什么
with the lucky loser and yeah,
毕竟我是幸运落败者
just try to focus
就是尽量专注
because last few days I don't even know I
因为前几天我根本不知道
have to play today.
今天要不要上场
So, and it's very enjoy the crowd
所以很享受现场的气氛
and enjoy the court and play one
享受这片球场
of the best player in this year.
跟今年最好的球员之一交手
The the players I'm just very happy
我对自己的表现
for my performance and yeah really enjoy
非常满意 打得很享受
and I'm really happy to make it.
能赢下来我真的很开心
Yeah. question.
下一个问题
Had you been obviously you said he's
你刚说他今年状态很好
had a great year were you you someone
你自己是那种
that watches a lot of tennis.
会看很多网球的人吗？
Have you been like watching
你有没有一直在关注
his rise throughout the year?
他这一年的崛起？
Yeah. of course I mean he he's doing
当然 我是说他今天
very great job today and then you know
打得非常好
it's one young young guy and lot of story
他是个年轻人 故事很多
and where I see in the in the website
我在网站上看到过
or in the Instagram or whatever.
或者 Instagram 上
So I mean everybody know how how much
所以大家都知道
he can play how how is he level.
他能打成什么样 什么水平
So I mean for me just nothing to lose
所以我根本没什么可输
and then just play free
放开打就是了
and it's very very good for me.
这对我来说特别好
Ju just how important is that playing freely
放开打这件事有多重要
and being being a lucky loser
作为幸运落败者
is is it a free shot?
是不是等于白赚一场？
Yeah, I mean that's that's you know nothing
对 我是说确实
can lose and and loser ready
没什么可输
and I don't I don't know I
而且我本来都不知道
can play today is also his last day
今天能不能打 今天又是
and last day for the first round and also I
第一轮的最后一天
was like maybe five out in the in the qualies
而且我大概排在第五顺位
so it's a little bit far away
在资格赛那边 还差得远
so I don't think I can play
所以我以为轮不到我
but you know I'm happy that I can play.
但我很高兴我能上场
Yeah. Did you decide
你是后来才决定
that you were gonna stay
要留下来
after a while or did you have plans to go or?
还是本来就打算走？
Yeah, I have I
我本来
have plan like Wednesday night is my flight
订的是周三晚上的机票
but you know and I get in yesterday
但昨天我进签表了
and then you know of course I
所以当然
have to change my flight because I need
得改签 因为我要打球
to play and I need to play today.
今天就得打
Yeah.
是的
Can you talk about the the emotions
能说说当时的心情吗
when when you found out
就是你得知
that you were going to play?
自己能上场的时候
What was that like? Actually,
那是什么感觉？其实
I was in the I just finished
我当时刚做完
my morning like warm up
早上的热身
and I was sitting there in the lunch
正坐着吃午饭
with my coach and then we say,
和教练一起 我们说
"Okay, let's start a day
好 今天就这样开始
and then let's see what's going
看看会发生
on." And then they come to me,
什么事 然后他们过来
they tell me I can play.
告诉我我可以打
So, I I say, "Wow,
我就说 哇
that's that's great." I mean,
那太好了
nothing nothing to complain.
没什么可抱怨的
And even I wait two days already.
哪怕我已经等了两天
So, yeah, just go for it.
那就上吧
When did you find out you were playing?
你什么时候知道能打的？
Wednesday.
周三
Wait.
等等
Oh, sorry. Tuesday.
哦 抱歉 周二
Sorry. Yesterday. Yesterday.
抱歉 是昨天
Sorry. Sorry. Yesterday.
不好意思 就是昨天
What time? I think probably around 11:30
几点？大概十一点半
12 when I have the lounge.
到十二点 在球员休息室
Okay.
好
Yeah. Okay.
嗯 好的
So this is the first time you've won
这是你第一次
a match at the grand slam level.
在大满贯正赛赢球
Just how does that feel?
感觉怎么样？
Feeling great.
感觉很好
I mean first win
第一场胜利
be the guy like like number 13 in the world.
赢的就是世界第十三
I mean obviously that's very
这显然是
very good feeling for me and if I
非常好的感觉 而且如果
have to win my first match like this I'm okay
第一胜必须这样赢来
with lose five six time before.
那之前输五六次我也认
So yeah, so that's great.
所以真的很棒
Do you do you think something was wrong
你觉得是他今天
with him or did did you did you
状态有问题 还是说你
I I I don't know actually
其实我不知道
when he start game he's very strong
他一开场很强
and I feel the level the tension is very high
我能感觉到强度很高
and yeah I just try to try to focus on my job
我就是专注做自己的事
and play my game you know play
打我自己的球
with play like what I can do and test him
用我会的东西去试他
in everywhere with my slice
各个位置都试 用切削
with my you know go in return
用接发抢上去
and then push him back
把他往后逼
and it's really worked for me Right.
这一套真的奏效了
How would you describe
对那些从没看过你打球
for the people who've never seen you play,
没听过你名字的人
never heard of you,
你会怎么介绍自己
who you are, what your life story
你是谁 你的经历
is, and what type of game you have.
以及你是什么打法？
Actually my idol is like Andy Murray.
我的偶像是穆雷
I like to play like him as well.
我也想打成他那样
And I I practice like a few years in the Spain.
我在西班牙练过几年
So my games live like a Spanish style,
所以我的球偏西班牙风格
like you know, play very heavy like top spin.
上旋很重
And then and and this few years I try
这几年我在试着
to change a bit you know
做一些改变
because I I feel I need
因为我感觉自己需要
to improve something
提高一些东西
and to get more higher ranking high level.
才能打到更高的排名
So yeah I try to play more aggressive now
所以现在我打得更主动
and then get have I think I have good serve
我觉得我发球不错
and in the baseline I can I can defense I
底线能防守
can run and then I can go to a net.
能跑动 也能上网
So yeah
就是这样
a lot of people have ambitions
很多人都有野心
that are dreams.
也有梦想
What were your tennis dreams
在拿下大满贯第一胜之前
before you had this opportunity
你的网球梦想
to win your first match in a major like this?
是什么？
Actually that's you know
其实就是
to break the top 100 for sure.
打进世界前一百
That's my my goal when I was young
那是我小时候的目标
because in our country we don't
因为在我们国家
have a top 100 players.
以前没有前一百的球员
We just break this history maybe
这个历史被打破
in three four years ago.
大概是三四年前
So when I was young you know
所以我小的时候
the the people around me the the all
我身边所有人
the players looking just for break
所有球员的目标
the top 100 and then we are we make four
都是打进前一百
plays already in this two three years.
而这两三年我们已经有四个了
So of course we have a new goal right now
所以现在我们有了新目标
but this is the break top 100 is like when I
但打进前一百这件事
was junior to start a professional like player
从青少年转职业那会儿
is the my main goal.
就是我最大的目标
Yeah. And what would you say
那你怎么形容
to best describe the following
你在国内
that you have in your home country
受到的关注
and maybe the messages
还有那些消息
that you've been getting?
你都收到了什么？
Actually, when I
其实当时
when when I have a full one up in the sa
就是那天
when we have rain stop already
比赛因为下雨中断的时候
many people text me already
已经很多人给我发消息了
but I try to you know just focus on myself
但我尽量只关注自己
and I didn't reply any message
一条都没有回
and yeah just stay close with my coach
就是跟我教练待在一起
with my team and do what I can do.
跟团队一起 做我该做的
Of course, right now I receive message
当然现在我收到消息了
and I see some news already.
也看到一些新闻了
So, but I will just focus on my side
但我还是只管自己这边
and I have to play tomorrow.
而且我明天还有比赛
So, maybe I just talk with my family,
所以我可能只跟家人
my coach, my girlfriend and no more.
教练 女朋友说说话
Yeah.
嗯
Are are you based in China still?
你现在还常驻在国内吗？
Yeah, I would say yes.
算是吧
When I I I like to go back a bit, you know,
我喜欢时不时回去
the the season alone, you know,
光是一个赛季
you travel 11 or 10 months per year.
一年就要在外面十到十一个月
So when I have a little break,
所以只要有一点假期
I would like to go back and then to chill,
我就想回去休息
you know, is when my home was there.
毕竟家在那儿
So, you know, when I go back,
所以每次回去
I feel like real relaxed.
我都觉得特别放松
You're from Xinjiang.
你是新疆人
I born there, but I we I was grew up
我在那儿出生 但我是
in Huzhou.
在湖州长大的
And where we have the 250, that city,
就是有那站 250 的城市
I don't know if you heard that.
不知道你听没听过
And yeah, in I moved there.
我搬去那儿
It's already like 18 18 years.
已经十八年了
So, yeah.
就是这样
Guangha.
是……？
No. Ha.
不是
Ha.
嗯
Yeah. Huzhou.
对 湖州
Okay. Yeah.
好的
And how
那你
when did you start playing tennis?
是什么时候开始打网球的？
Probably like six around six maybe.
大概六岁左右吧
Around six years old.
六岁左右
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Six or five.
对 六岁或者五岁
Yeah. Yeah. But when I was young,
不过我小时候
we play like the softball.
打的是软式网球
I don't know if you were like mini tennis.
你们可能叫迷你网球
Okay.
好
Yeah. Maybe when I was eight also.
大概八岁的时候
We have that tournament.
就有那种比赛了
We have that like match
有那种对抗
when when we are in the kids.
小孩子之间的
And then when I grew up a bit, you know,
等我长大一点
I started play real tennis like
才开始打真正的网球
when I was maybe eight and a half or nine,
大概八岁半或者九岁
you know.
差不多
Were you influenced by Li Na?
你受过李娜的影响吗？
Yeah.
有
How important has she been?
她对你有多重要？
For sure.
肯定有影响
I mean the first Grand Slam winner Chinese
中国第一个大满贯冠军
and I think when we are young
我想我们小的时候
when probably when shooting
大概她拿下
the grand slam I just maybe 10 years old
大满贯那会儿 我大概十岁
or more or less.
差不多吧
I'm not sure which year is it
具体哪一年我记不清了
and you know every everybody want
反正每个人都想
to be like her
成为她那样
but you know in the men's side
但在男子这边
but we don't have top 100 players
我们连前一百的球员都没有
so you know it's little bit different we
所以有点不一样
have a lot great player in women's side
女子那边有很多好球员
but in men's side is not that much
男子这边就没那么多
last question
最后一个问题
yeah your next match you're playing I don't
你下一场的对手
know if you know you're playing yeah
不知道你清不清楚
you played him a few years ago
你几年前跟他打过
in a challenger do you do you remember
在一站挑战赛上
that match and yeah
那场球你还记得吗？
actually not that much
其实记得不太清了
because I practiced him
因为我今年
in Cincinnati this year and in Wimbledon
在辛辛那提和温网
and in the grass season as well.
还有草地赛季都和他练过
I mean he he he changed a lot
他变了很多
and he play very great tennis right now
现在打得非常好
is much more different than two years ago.
和两年前完全不一样了
So I would not look back.
所以我不会往回看